<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-14T22:55:41-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dan Land</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><author><name>Dan Halpern</name></author><entry><title type="html">Aaron’s Spinoff Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Aarons-Spinoff/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aaron’s Spinoff Analysis" /><published>2020-12-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-12-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Aarons-Spinoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Aarons-Spinoff/">&lt;p&gt;Aaron’s Holdings (originally trading as AAN) is a retail Lease to Own (LTO) firm with two main business segments: Virtual Lease to Own, and Brick and Mortar Retail Lease To Own.  Earlier this year management announced their intention to spinoff their retail business from their virtual least to own segment in all stock 2:1 ratio.  Somewhat unusually, AAN will be the &lt;em&gt;spinoff&lt;/em&gt; component.  Aarons created a holding company for the SpinCo and will rename the RemainCo to Progressive concurrently with the spinoff transaction.  At the onset, the virtual LTO component looks more attractive.  Since the acquisition of Progressive Finance Holdings in 2014 for $700m.  The Progressive segment has continued to grow like gangbusters with an average annual growth rate of around 25% compounded.  The recent activity separating AAN from Progressive (PRG) returns the two segments to their separate pre-2014 formats.  However, the predictable earnings, large target market, and management’s conservative business plan make AAN a hidden gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;when issued&lt;/em&gt; trading eventually moved the value of the firms quite significantly.  With PRG trading at $59.45 just one day (Dec 2nd) after being publicly available on the NYSE and AAN closing the day at $18.25 management was clearly able to unlock additional value from the PRG unit.  At these closing prices PRG has a market capitalization of around 5% less than the original parent while AAN is now valued at just $575m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe there is a compelling case to invest in the Aaron’s retail spinoff.  I will present an analysis covering the following approaches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insider Movement / Activity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cash Flows &amp;amp; Business Quality Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Industry Comps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don’t believe any of the above indications are strong enough on their own, I find the LTO trends in concert with the consistent message delivered above to deliver a strong message: &lt;em&gt;the risk to reward of investing in AAN is quite attractive&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insider-movement--activity&quot;&gt;Insider Movement / Activity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to investigate here is “&lt;em&gt;where do the company’s existing management find themselves after the spinoff?”&lt;/em&gt; Starting at the top, we find &lt;strong&gt;John W. Robinson&lt;/strong&gt;. Robinson is the President and CEO of the pre-spin company, and was formerly the CEO of pre-acquisition Progressive.  He will move to Chairman of the Board of Aaron’s SpinCo.  Also moving to Aarons SpinCo is &lt;strong&gt;Douglas Lindsay&lt;/strong&gt; who previously served as President at the pre-spin company.  Lindsay will now act as CEO of Aaron’s SpinCo  Finally, &lt;strong&gt;C. Kelly Wall&lt;/strong&gt; will serve as CFO of Aaron’s SpinCo.  Mr Wall previously served as interim CFO to parent.  Before that Wall served as Vice President of Finance, Treasury and Investor Relations of Parent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messers Robinson and Wall may be the two individuals most capable of assessing both companies.  The fact that Robinson ran the pre-acquisition Progressive and continued to running the combined organization indicates that he understands that he sees greater potential in the retail spinoff.  As the CFO of the combined companies, we would expect Mr Wall to also have a unique understanding of the two companies’ resulting financial situation.  I think this is the weakest buy signal we will discuss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;financial-statements--business-quality-analysis&quot;&gt;Financial Statements &amp;amp; Business Quality Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strength of Aaron’s SpinCo’s value proposition can be seen in the pro-forma (as a mater of form - i.e. as if spun-off) financial statements.  &lt;strong&gt;The Book Value of Aaron’s SpinCo as of Sep 30th (most recent quarter end) was ~$620m&lt;/strong&gt;, this amounts to $18.35/shr.  At this estimate, the price to book (P/B) value of Aaron’s comes out to 600/620 = 0.96 as of Dec 2nd 2020.  The proposition gets more attractive as we move to analyze the cash flows.  Reported Net Earnings for the Nine Months ended Sep 30th are reported as $(269m).  But we know better than to take this number at face value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management decided to revalue Aaron’s Goodwill account in March when stores were closed, and the future prospects of the Corona Virus were most uncertain.  The impairment of Goodwill accounted for a whopping $447m operating expense on the statement of earnings! Looking deeper into the Statement of Cash Flows, we find a more compelling story: cash flows from Operating Activities totaled $337m, and the total change in cash and cash equivalents was $384m in the first 3 quarters of 2020 as opposed to cash flows of $132m in over the same period in 2019.
Cash flows accounted for more than half of the enterprise value of Aaron’s!  Now, because GAAP income statements are accrual based, we must be careful about provisions for bad debt and depreciation of unrecoverable leased merchandise.  However the author is not materially concerned since we have established a comfortable buffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cash flows provide us with two ways at investigating the earnings yield of Aarons.  Using the conservative TTM Adjusted EBITDA shared shared in the Roadshow presentation on 11/19 we get $206m/$616m = 0.33 which is quite compelling.  The FCF (after CapEx and other adjustments) provides a somewhat tamer $75/$616 = 0.12.  S&amp;amp;P Earnings yields are currently averaging 2-4% depending on where the information is pulled from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the current state of finances does seems attractive, we have learned from Warren Buffet that it is similarly important to identify strong business plans / management as well.  Aarons management has set out on a much needed cost savings initiative.  In the first quarter of 2020 the firm initiated a real estate optimization program wherein they are consolidating geographic footprints of neighboring stores to dramatically reduce expenses.  Thus far this has resulted in the closure and consolidation of 88 company owned/operated stores, with plans to close an additional 35 stores over the next 3-6 months.  Long term, management expects to close approximately 300 (approximately 1/5th of all stores) additional stores over the next 3-4 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strategy passes the sniff test.  While Aarons.com continues to grow at prodigious rates the stores are increasingly used as warehouses to ship online purchases.  Moreover, the retail operating expense are clearly one of the larger cost centers for the company.  Based on historic closures rates compared to top-line sales, I believe that management has the ability to undertake this task with minimal reduction in revenues.  Based on the projections provided in the Roadshow presentation, investors can conservatively expect a decrease in revenues in the first year of operation followed by modest gains YoY following.  However this &lt;em&gt;does not mean that profits will decline&lt;/em&gt;.  Based on what we know about the corporate strategy its safe to believe that profits will stay consistent or climb modestly based on the more significant reduction in cost of revenues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will conclude this section with a lesson from Warren Buffet and Charlie Munger on downsizing:  &lt;em&gt;It is no fun being the village blacksmith when the car comes along, however Munger can not name a single business ruined by downsizing; he could think of many ruined by bloat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;valuation-by-industry-comps&quot;&gt;Valuation By Industry Comps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we will investigate the value of Aarons based on its industry peers.  I feel it is important to emphasize &lt;strong&gt;industry comps do not indicate the intrinsic value of a firm.  This methodology is susceptible to overvaluations of the market or industry at large.  Therefore it should only be used in concert with other more conservative valuation approaches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Values all in Thousands&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table-full&quot;&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Market Cap&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;EBIT&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Book Value of Equity&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Cash From Ops&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;P/E Ratio&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;P/B Ratio&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Ops Cash Yield&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Rent-A-Center&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,930,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$171,300&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$542,337&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$296,226&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;11.27&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;3.56&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;0.15&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Big Lots (Est.) &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,840,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$231,036.8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,328,160&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$471,581&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;7.96&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;1.39&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;0.256&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;First Cash&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$2,840,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$100,592&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,243,926&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$177,366&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;28.23&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;2.28&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;0.06&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Conns (Est.) &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$404,690&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$83,040&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$518,586&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$305,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;4.87&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;0.78&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;0.75&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Wayfair&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$23,800,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$161,592&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$(1,459,586)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,209,988&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;147.28&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;-16.31&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;0.05&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Target&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$87,650,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$3,816,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$13,319,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$7,044,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;22.97&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;6.58&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;0.08&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Aarons&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$641,820&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$55,498&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$620,581&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$337,238&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;11.56&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;1.03&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;0.53&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These financials provide us insight into how the market values companies compared to their financials.  We can apply this to understand what the valuation of Aarons might be if it was given the same market treatment across any given metric.  The following table demonstrates various discounts or premiums that Aarons is trading at compared to a given peer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;P/E Implied Value of AAN&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;P/B Implied Value of AAN&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Ops Cash Yield Implied Value of AAN&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Rent-A-Center&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$625,284&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$2,208,445&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$2,197,205&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Big Lots (Est.)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$441,992&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$859,738&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,315,825&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;First Cash&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,566,867&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,416,845&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$5,399,885&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Conns (Est.)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$270,466&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$484,284&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$447,468&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Wayfair&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$8,173,996&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$—&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$6,633,342&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Target&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1,274,738&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$4,083,935&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$4,196,325&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aarons (Implied)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$2,058,890&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$1,810,649&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$3,365,008&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Earnings and cashflow estimated by multiplying operating results ((Q1+Q2)*1.6).  Results include $463m sale of Distribution Centers &lt;em&gt;how many times can they do that??&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Earnings and cashflow estimated by multiplying operating results ((Q1+Q2)*1.6).  Results rely on 2019 EBIT due to negative figures in 2020 from abnormal activity and recording&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is clearly a huge upside potential. Considering the book value of Aarons already includes accounting for bad debt in the assets assigned to leases, I believe this is a conservative and attractive opportunity with generous reward opportunity compared to the risk.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dan Halpern</name></author><category term="Trades" /><category term="Spinoff" /><summary type="html">Aaron’s Holdings (originally trading as AAN) is a retail Lease to Own (LTO) firm with two main business segments: Virtual Lease to Own, and Brick and Mortar Retail Lease To Own. Earlier this year management announced their intention to spinoff their retail business from their virtual least to own segment in all stock 2:1 ratio. Somewhat unusually, AAN will be the spinoff component. Aarons created a holding company for the SpinCo and will rename the RemainCo to Progressive concurrently with the spinoff transaction. At the onset, the virtual LTO component looks more attractive. Since the acquisition of Progressive Finance Holdings in 2014 for $700m. The Progressive segment has continued to grow like gangbusters with an average annual growth rate of around 25% compounded. The recent activity separating AAN from Progressive (PRG) returns the two segments to their separate pre-2014 formats. However, the predictable earnings, large target market, and management’s conservative business plan make AAN a hidden gem.</summary></entry></feed>